<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>David Clausen</title>
    <description>Aspiring Web Developer and Ex-Chef. Currently Looking for Full-Stack Opportunities.
</description>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 23:12:50 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 23:12:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tic Tac Tie</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tic Tac Tie was an accidental pun made while discussing the program’s computer logic it used
against the player. It was suppose to be simple and aim to always create a draw. Hence the ‘tie’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I did find one win condition it can’t seem to beat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is okay as it was my first ‘AI’ I’ve made to play against someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t do much design on this one. I may revist it. Main goal was to see how
quickly I could go from concept in my head to fully functional. I had to get up early
take a long car ride downtown. I felt I had all the kinks and issues worked out
in my head. How i’d style it, the html layout and the javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it felt great to write HUGE chunks of it with little testing before finishing.
Still a lot of micro tweaks, but overall it works great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kalcode.github.io/tictactie/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Tic Tac Tie&lt;/a&gt;, as usual you can find the code on my github.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/updates/2016/04/14/tictactie/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/updates/2016/04/14/tictactie/</guid>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pomodoro Technique</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently did a project that required you to create a Pomodoro timer, a productivity tool. I am a
big fan of their technique. Following it, even loosely, has greatly improved my
ability to focus, study and in general knock out projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out their website to get an idea what it’s about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/pomodoro.png&quot; alt=&quot;pomodoro&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://pomodorotechnique.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Pomodoro Technique Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am really proud of this, I think its not only the best looking app I’ve but the most functional too.
Here is the link currently to my timer &lt;a href=&quot;http://kalcode.github.io/pomodoro/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Promodoro Timer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the Jquery UI &lt;em&gt;A LOT&lt;/em&gt; less this time. I used it for some warning boxes on inputs and the slide out settings, but
the rest of the animation is just custom CSS animation. Great practice learning that as I feel vastly more
comfortable rolling my own animation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comment below and let me know what you think. Hopefully you find it as useful as
I do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/updates/2016/04/12/pomodoro/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/updates/2016/04/12/pomodoro/</guid>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Big Display Calculator</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wanted to recreate the classic old style calculator especially their functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding less use for bootstrap as I get a handle on CSS. Bootstrap is nice to have but
it often feels like throwing too much at something that really doesn’t need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/calculator-big-display.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;calculator&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out at my github, live version here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://kalcode.github.io/calculator/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Calculator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/updates/2016/04/04/big-display-calculator/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/updates/2016/04/04/big-display-calculator/</guid>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Twitch Watcher</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fairly straight forward app. Handling JSON from a get request but a lot more
information coming in and not consistent. So that helped learn some new obstacles and
how to hurdle them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/twitch-watcher.png&quot; alt=&quot;snapshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am liking the idea of going clean and simple. The list is rather simple to update,
so creating one designed for someone else favorite streamers would be trivial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kalcode.github.io/twitchstreamer/&quot;&gt;Twitch Watcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that was exciting this project was saving results in a remote area like
a ‘temp’ database. Found a website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;browsers-rant&quot;&gt;Browsers rant&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latest frustration has been Firefox, it seems like Opera, Safari Chrome and even
Edge all have similar features and the way they deal with them. Firefox on the other hand
is the edge case browser now. It seems it mostly due to being very strict in following
the specifications, so I guess they can’t be faulted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/updates/2016/03/28/twitch-stream/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/updates/2016/03/28/twitch-stream/</guid>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wiki Search Viewer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/wiki-banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;snapshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latest project is a simple get request to wiki for your search. I mostly liked
the design I settled on. Simple and clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First time trying out animation, I am using Jquery UI for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kalcode.github.io/wikisearch/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Wiki Search Viewer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/updates/2016/03/24/wiki-viewer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/updates/2016/03/24/wiki-viewer/</guid>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Local Weather Project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Project was creating a weather app that gets your current location
via browser. I used the recommend weather app API &lt;a href=&quot;http://openweathermap.org/api&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;OpenWeatherMap&lt;/a&gt;.
Relatively straight forward project. Few days ago I did the project with the
random quote API, so that was very helpful here. Parsing the JSON took a short
learning curve but otherwise not very troublesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really starting to get a very comfortable feel with CSS. CSS was probably the more
intimidating of the HTML frontend stuff. It always seems like a fight to get something
the way you want it. Lately that doesn’t seem to be the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well here it is and my code will always be available on my github : Live &lt;a href=&quot;http://kalcode.github.io/localweather/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Local Weather App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;css-frustrations-rant-warning&quot;&gt;CSS Frustrations /rant-warning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things like clearfix on everything, negative margins and in simple things like fighting a solution to center stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;clear&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;both&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;!important&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;padding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;!important&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;z-index&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;-999999&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;!important&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just seemed like everything was a ‘hacky’ solution. Things are getting a lot more clear for me
and I am sure that in part to be able to exclusively use CSS3 and ditch a lot of the old
hacky stuff due to browser compatibility but also getting a better understanding of the
basics have been great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next few projects will have more focus on making things look much cleaner and
more attractive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/updates/2016/03/20/localweather/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/updates/2016/03/20/localweather/</guid>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Profile Page</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kalcode.github.io/&quot;&gt;My Profile Page&lt;/a&gt;, first start of the projects.
Profile page is a good way to start it, so I was excited to get started. I am
not to good with CSS but I really liked the way this came out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess its a good start to a portfolio and soon I can add projects to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/updates/2016/03/15/profile/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/updates/2016/03/15/profile/</guid>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jekyll and Blogging</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Got Jekyll up and running for the start of my blog. Gonna use this to motivate myself
to spend some time reflecting on the projects I’ve been doing. Trying to learn a lot
in the timeframe I have has definitely crammed more than I can reflect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these next more freeform projects coming up I should be able to test myself in
how far I have come and give myself opportunities to put myself outside my comfort zone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/assets/images/sample-banner-image-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;jeklly&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll was a fun process. This theme is very nice, a few tweaks here and there to change out
some images, color theme and social icons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-up&quot;&gt;Setting up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some reason Github wouldn’t build my pages even though locally I wasn’t getting
 any errors. So instead I’ve set it up locally to build the site and then push
 it to my git page via a batch file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also required having a separate dev config too, which was interesting. On my
side everything build flawlessly and pushing it seems to have no issues as it
no longer requiring Github to builds the pages. This also means I can use
whatever plug-in I desire.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/updates/2016/03/10/jekyll/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/updates/2016/03/10/jekyll/</guid>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
